Edward McMillan

Okemos, Michigan, United States



djmcmillan93@gmail.com



6789515143



linkedin.com/in/dj-mcmillan-56400028

Summary

Currently a full-time employee at Playmakers Athletic Footwear & Apparel. Worked in a variety of roles including:

- 11 years in teaching & coaching
- 7 years in management
- 5 years in web development

Solution-oriented problem solver. Excels at abstracting problems to get to the root issue, which allows him to clearly see the big picture and take an efficient and effective course of action. His resiliency also allows him to take setbacks in stride and adjust his course as needed.

Worked collaboratively with large teams to develop a suite of software tools that drove e-commerce sales from less than \$0.5 million to over \$15 million in 3 years using tools such as:

JavaScript - Node.js - Express.js - React.js - jQuery - AWS - HTML5 - CSS3 - - Bootstrap - Shopify Plus - Ruby -Liquid - Google loud - MongoDB - MySQL - GraphQL - Git - GitHub - and many more

Looking for opportunities that will allow me to live in the Raleigh, NC area.

Experience

Web Developer

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Apr 2018 - Present (4 years 10 months)

Drove Commerce growth from less than \$0.5 mil/year to over \$15 mil/year over 3 years Eliminated major eCommerce order processing errors and inefficiencies via invoice auto-printing including detailed order & product information, leading to significantly increased productivity and client satisfaction

Maximized eCommerce product buildout speed through the utilization of multiple automation tools, allowing for quicker inventory turnover and ROI

Minimized customer wait times by developing a custom Queue Management app in order to consistently provide a exceptional customer experiences and increase customer retention Implemented dozens of custom-built applications that have allowed both online and in-store operations to scale efficiently and effectively by eliminating wasted time and money.

Team Leader (Manager)

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Jun 2016 - Present (6 years 8 months)

Utilized leadership and connection skills to develop staff and prepare them for successful careers, both at Playmakers and beyond

Clinic Outreach Coordinator and Instructor

Playmakers Athletic Footwear and Apparel

Jan 2015 - Present (8 years 1 month)

Developed, coordinated, and taught hundreds of non-profit health & wellness-based outreach clinics

Good Form Running Clinic Instructor and Guest Advocate

Tortoise & Hare Sports

May 2014 - Jan 2015 (9 months)

Coordinate and schedule Good Form Running clinics both at the stores and at various events outside

Instructed Good Form Running Classes, creating a fun and informative environment where learning best thrives



🛼 Good Form Running Clinic Director

Big Peach Running Co.

Oct 2013 - May 2014 (8 months)

Recruited, trained, and developed Good Form Running Coaches to ensure that they provided the best possible experience for the students

Coordinated and scheduled Good Form Running clinics



Point of Sale System Coordinator

Big Peach Running Co.

Jul 2013 - May 2014 (11 months)

Accurately entered and received dozens of product orders each week, correctly including any applicable vendor discounts

Punctually added product SKU's and UPC's into the point of sale system

Assisted in the transition and implementation of the new point of sale system at each store, writing Excel VBA code to convert and consolidate SKU's

Guest Advocate

Big Peach Running Company

Sep 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 9 months)

Paralegal's Assistant

Law Offices of Gary M. Shapiro

May 2009 - Aug 2010 (1 year 4 months)

Worked with paralegal to increase productivity of the office by streamlining essential tasks

Created financial spreadsheet for the office to identify flow of assets

Helped conduct research to obtain crucial information on clients and defendants

🦚 Tent Manager

TNT Fireworks

May 2007 - Jul 2010 (3 years 3 months)

Conducted pre-operations analysis to estimate necessary workforce, resulting in maximum operational efficiency

Oversaw the financial aspects of everyday operation, minimizing unnecessary expenditures and maximizing profits

Kept precise financial books in order to accurately determine outflows, inflows and gross profits Managed the general operations of the tent in order to most effectively capitalize from the sales, resulting in an increase in gross profit from 2009 to 2010 of 83%

Education

Michigan State University

Coding Bootcamp, Full Stack Development

May 2022 - Nov 2022

Gained desirable technical skills and invaluable industry knowledge to accelerate my journey through Development.

Gr Georgia Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science, Management; Pre-Law, Logistics, Materials, and Supply Chain Management

Aug 2007 - May 2012

BSM Concentration in Operations & Supply Chain Management.

Scholarship Athlete (Cross Country/Indoor & Outdoor Track).

Skills

User Interface Design • Web Applications • Bootstrap • Adobe Photoshop • Back-End Web Development • Front-End Development • WordPress • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • HTML5 • Full-Stack Development